Guide to the North Star Mining Company and Associated Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Series XI. Other Mining Companies and Associations: The papers in this series (90-93) are arranged alphabetically by company and then by record type (see Summary Outline of Record Types, pages 33-34). The majority of the companies are Grass Valley mines, of which many were eventually purchased by Hague and the North Star. The records of A. Chavanne & Co., early owners of the Rocky Bar, consist of some of the earliest deeds in the collection, chronicling the history of claims in the Massachusetts-New York Hill area. The Chavanne company took over the Rocky Bar from the Mount Hope Company, which is also represented here. Michael Brennan, superintendent of the Rocky Bar mine in 1858, was involved in the financial scandal that led to Chavanne's takeover and the collection contains a copy of his suicide letter (folder 1961A).
Three of the groups are from areas other than Nevada County. Murphy Mining company was in Nye County, Nevada, which was probably the location of the Twin River Mining District and the Twin River Consolidated Mining Company (Boxes 93, folders 2068-74). Since Hague was president of the Twin River company, he may explain its presence in this collection as well as other non-Grass Valley records. The Yaqui-Providencia Mining Company (folders 2083-84) was incorporated in Arizona and worked mines in Mexico, perhaps in Sonora. Records of non-mining groups include American Powder Packing Company, Marysville and Nevada Power and Water Company, and the Mine Workers Protection.
Unidentified mining records are at the end of this series. There are deeds recording the transfer of land and mineral claims in and around Grass Valley from 1857 to 1899. Several maps show the situation of claims in the area in 1867, at the turn of the century, and in 1930. Also included are photographs of unidentified buildings and workers, as well as some landscape prints from the Giant Gold Mining Company.
Series XII. Printed Material: This series consists primarily of chronologically arranged printed pieces about mining or Grass Valley found among the corporate records. There are local newspapers from Grass Valley, including issues with histories of the mines. Other printed material centers on mining, including a special centennial issue of the Virginia City Times and a 1949 publication, Drama of the Comstock. A 1902 pamphlet on Nevada County by a local promotion committee contains histories as well as illustrations of the mines (Box 2111). Articles on the Grass Valley Historical Museum document its founding.
Oversize contains material from Series I-XII. The arrangement, based on the size of the material, parallels the order of the collection. SUMMARY OUTLINE OF RECORD TYPES The following is an outline of the arrangement of the papers used for each series. EXECUTIVE RECORDS --Incorporation, By-Laws, Minutes ---Certificate of incorporation ---Articles of incorporation ---By-laws ---Minutes of directors/stockholders meetings ---Copies of minutes and material from meetings --Correspondence ---New York to San Francisco ---Received at San Francisco ---Sent by San Francisco ---Received at Grass Valley ---Sent by Grass Valley --Insurance --Accident Documents --Agreements, Claims, Deeds --Court Actions --Special Projects and Reports --Stock Documents ---Ledger ---Subscriptions ---Receipts of stock sold ---Transfer journal ---Transfer slips ---Assessment ledger ---Statements of issues of stock ---Register of stockholders ---Names and addresses of stockholders ---List of stockholders ---Certificates ---Sale of delinquent stock ---Irrevocable stock power ---Proxies ---Account of sale of stock for assessment and charges ---Receipts for stock certificate tax OPERATION RECORDS --Monthly reports --Weekly reports --Daily journal --Maps and diagrams --Mine development --Maps and diagrams ORE AND BULLION RECORDS FINANCIAL RECORDS --Annual statement --Ledger --Cash book --Journal --Monthly statement --Tabulated statements --Analyzed statements --Trial Balances --Monthly tribute statements --Various accounts --Superintendent's statements and drafts, or --Statements of receipts and disbursements, or --Paid drafts, vouchers, receipts --Bills sent to secretary for payment --Receipts --Lists of drafts drawn --Drafts --Bank book --Check stubs --Checks PAY ROLL RECORDS --Pay roll Records --Time books INVENTORY RECORDS OTHER MATERIAL
Appendix 1: Officers of mining companies
Most of the men listed wrote letters in their official capacity and this material can be found in the correspondence sections of Executive Records. Corporate officers are often mentioned in the minutes, which are also found in Executive Records.
EMPIRE COMPANY
Presidents
Hague, James D. 1897 *
Bourn, William B. 1899-07
* Hague's other positions include: president of Twin River Consolidated Mining Company; president of Original Empire Mill and Mining Company.
Vice-presidents: Griffith, Edwin L. 1899
Secretaries: Ward, J. Walter 1899-04
Superintendents: Watt, Mr., 1867; McKay, David Jr., 1884-86; Starr, George W., 1892-07
GOLD HILL MINING COMPANY
Presidents: Ivory, M. B., 1877-78; Coleman, Edward, 1878-90; Hopkins, E. W., 1890-1900
Vice-presidents: Scott, H. [T.], 1890-99; Hopkins, Timothy 1899
Secretaries: Ogden, F[rederick], 1877-78; Hill, George W. 1878; Grow, C. A., 1890-1900
Superintendents: Lord, George, 1877-[96]; Dawson, F. R. P., 1896-97
GRANITE HILL MINING COMPANY
Secretaries
Roberts, E. A. 1897-98
Presidents
Kirk, H. S.
Superintendents
Harvey, James F. 1895
Phillips, T. F. 1896-99
Walker, Robert 1899-1900
GRASS VALLEY WATER COMPANY
Presidents
Bourn, William B. 1885-89
Hague, James D. [1889]-99
Vice-president
Bourn, William B. 1889-96
Bishop, Charles R. 1896-99
Secretaries
Ward, J. Walter 1897-99
Superintendents
Walker, Robert 1894-98
NEW YORK HILL MINING COMPANY
Presidents
Pinkham, S 1874-75
Byrne, James K. 1875-76
Becker, B. A. 1876-78
Watt, Robert 1878-89
Morrow, R. F. 1879, pro-term president
Bourn, William B. 1889-93
Hague, James D. 1893-94
Vice-president
Hague, James D. 1890-93
Bourn, William B. 1893-94
Secretaries
Jennings, David A. 1874-75 *
*
Jennings other positions include: secretary of Mint Gold and Silver Mining Company, Mortimer Mining Company, Mammoth Silver Mining Company; Hamburg Mining Company, Ward Beecher Consolidated Mill & Mining Company, Original Hidden Treasure Mining Company, Emmet Consolidated Mining Company, Magenta Consolidated Gold Mining Company, and American Powder Packing Company; treasurer of New York Hill Company.
Herrmann, F. J. 1875-78
Leighton, John B. 1879-89
Jennings, David A. 1889-94
Superintendents
Snyder, Jos. 1874-76
Johnston, George 1876-89
NORTH STAR MINING COMPANY
Presidents
Peachy, Archibald C. 1867
Dean, W. E. 1868-69
Harmon, A. K. P. 1869-78
Parkhurst, D. L. 1879
Dean, W. E. 1879-84
Durbrow, A. K. 1884-87 (old North Star Company)
Bourn, William B. 1884-87
Hague, James D. 1887-99
Agnew, George B. 1908-15
Vice-presidents
Cutter, H. F. 1885-89
Bourn, William B. 1887, 1890-92
Secretaries
Colburn, T. W. 1867
Jennings, David A. 1870-97
Ward, J. Walter 1897-1900
Pagan, W. D. 1900-07, 1922-28
Dodge, Cleveland E. 1928
Assistant secretaries
Olmsted, William N. 1888-90, 1892
Pagan, W. D. 1892-99
Superintendents
Coleman, Edward 1867
Rodda, William Henry 1867
Beckwith, Henry 1868
Crossman, James H. 1868
Hoyt, Dudley 1869-72
Moore, Stephen 1872
Stoddart, A. W. 1884-85
Abadie, Emilie R. 1886-94
Marshall, Thomas 1894-95
Robert, P. R. 1895-96
Foote, Arthur De Wint [1896]-1929
Bedford, Robert H. 1920-31
ROCKY BAR MINING COMPANY
President
Berton, Francis 1863
Coleman, Edward 1878
Hague, James D. 1893
Secretaries
Hill, George W. 1878
Marshall, Thomas 1893
Superintendents
Chavanne, L. 1863-[66]
Silvester, Henry 1885
TRIBUTE MINING COMPANY
President
Heyman, Jacob 1879
Taylor, M. [C.] 1879-96
Hague, James D. 1896
Secretaries
Cheva[nne], Edouard 1863
Weissbein, Jacob 1879-96
Marshall, Thomas 1896
Cornish -- California -- Grass Valley; Gold mines and mining -- California -- Grass Valley; Hydraulic engineering -- California; Labor unions -- California -- Grass Valley; Mine pumps; Miners -- California -- Labor unions; Mines and mineral resources -- California -- Grass Valley; Mining engineering -- California -- Grass Valley; Mining machinery; California -- Economic conditions; Grass Valley (Calif.) -- History; Nevada County (Calif.) -- History; Nye County (Nev.); Account books; Agreements -- United States; Bankbooks -- United States; Cashbooks -- United States; Check Stubs -- United States; Checks -- United States; Daybooks -- United States; Deeds -- United States; Insurance policies -- United States; Letterpress copybooks -- United States; Maps -- United States; Minutes -- United States; Payrolls -- United States; Receipts -- United States; Gold miners -- California; Mining Engineers, -- California; Abadie, Emilie R.; Agnew, George B.; Bourn, William B.; Dawson, F. R. P.; Foote, A. D. (Arthur DeWint), 1849-1933; Grow, C. A.; Hague, James D. (James Duncan), 1836-1908; Hammond, John Hays, 1855-1936; Hopkins, E. W.; Howe, Ernest, 1875-1932; Jennings, David A., d. 1897; Johnston, George, fl. 1876-1889; Lord, George; Marshall, Thomas, fl. 1890-1896; Phillips, T. F.; Robert, P. R.; Stoddart, A. W.; Walker, Robert, fl. 1894-1904; Ward, J. Walter; Champion Mines; Empire Mines and Investment Company; Empire Star Mines Company Limited; Gold Hill Mining Company; Granite Hill Mining & Development Company; Grass Valley Water Company; Massachusetts Hill Mining Company; Mine Workers Protection League (Grass Valley, Calif.); New York Hill Mining Company; North Star Gold Mining Company; North Star Mines Company; North Star Mining Company; Original Empire Mill and Mining Company; Rocky Bar Gold Mining Company; Stockbridge Quartz Mining Company; Tribute Mining Company; Twin River Mining District (Nye County, Nev.)
- Empire Mines and Investment Company, 1902-24; Series I; 0.75
  Scope and Contents
  Sometime prior to 1902, this company was known as Original Empire Mill and Mining Company (Series XI). In 1929 Empire merged with the North Star mines and became Empire Star Mines Company Ltd. (Series II).
  - EXECUTIVE RECORDS
    - Annual report and accounts, 1902 Dec 31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Agreements, claims, deeds
      Grouped by transaction (A to B, B to C, etc.) and arranged chronologically.
      - Land, mineral rights sold to Lloyd P. Larue, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Land, mineral rights sold to Lloyd P. Larue, 1909-15 (Box 1, Folder 3-28)
      - Land, mineral rights sold to Lloyd P. Larue, 1915-17 (Box 2, Folder 29-39)
      - Land, mineral rights sold by Lloyd P. Larue to William B. Bourn, 1911-12 (Box 2, Folder 40-41)
      - Land, mineral rights sold by William B. Bourn to Empire, 1905, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 42-44)
      - Land, mineral rights sold by Lloyd P. Larue to Empire, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Land, mineral rights sold by Lloyd P. Larue to Empire, 1916-17 (Box 2, Folder 46-47)
      - Land, mineral rights sold by others to Empire, 1916-18 (Box 3, Folder 48-52)
      - Land, mineral rights sold by others to Empire, 1918-20 (Box 3, Folder 53-56)
      - Mineral patents, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 57)
      - Claim of Panama Lode, 1917 Oct 10 (Box 3, Folder 58)
      - Indenture, Empire to John T. Hopper (unsigned), 1924 Oct (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - OTHER MATERIAL
    - Photographic postcards of mine workers, ca. 1906-18 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Empire Star Mines Company Ltd., 1930-41; Series II; 0.5
  Formed by the merge of the Empire (Series I) and the North Star (Series VIII) in 1929, this company was succeeded by the New Verde Mines Company (Series XI).
  - EXECUTIVE RECORDS
    - Accident Documents
      - California Industrial Accident Commission trial, 1936 Aug 12 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1929-30 (Box 3, Folder 62-63)
    - Court actions
      - Empire Star vs. Grass Valley Bullion Mines (U.S. District Court), 1935 Oct 23 (Box 3, Folder 64)
      - Empire Star vs. Cooley Butler, Walter Butler, Fred Kalenborn, et al (California Superior Court), 1941 Jan 8 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Special projects and reports
      - [Gladys-Belle Mine, report by Rush T. Sill], 1930 Apr 1 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - OTHER MATERIAL
    - Orders for equipment, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 67)
      - Design for book cover, Gold: The Story of the Empire Star Mines, n.d.
        Related Archival Materials note
        See: Oversize, Box 94, folder 2123
- Gold Hill Mining Company, 1877-1903; Series III; 17.25
  Gold Hill was taken over by North Star in 1903 and information on the mine after that date can be found in the North Star records (Series VIII).
  - EXECUTIVE RECORDS
    - Incorporation, By-Laws, Minutes
      - By-laws, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 68)
      - Minutes of directors/stockholders meetings, 1877-1903 (Box 3a, Folder 69, Box 3b, Folder 70)
      - Copies of minutes and material from meetings, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Correspondence
      - Received at San Francisco, 1884 (Box 4, Folder 72)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1890-93 (Box 4, Folder 73-85)
        See also: Oversize, Box 94, folder 2124
      - Received at San Francisco, 1894
        See: Sent by Grass Valley, Box 9, folder 190
      - Received at San Francisco, 1895-96 (Box 4, Folder 86-94)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1896-97 (Box 5, Folder 95-104)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1897-99 (Box 6, Folder 105-29)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1899-1903 (Box 7, Folder 130-62)
      - Sent by San Francisco, 1890-95 (Box 8a, Folder 163)
      - Sent by San Francisco, 1896-1903
        See: Folders 87-162, copies are filed with letters received at San Francisco.
      - Received at Grass Valley, 1899-1903 (Box 8, Folder 164-89)
      - Sent by Grass Valley, 1890-1898; 1902 (Box 9a, Folder 190, Box 9b, Folder 191, Box 9c, Folder 192)
    - Agreements, claims, deeds
      - Agreement, 1882 (Box 9, Folder 193)
      - Agreement, 1890 (Box 9, Folder 194)
      - Agreements, 1896-97 (Box 9, Folder 195)
    - Court actions
      - In re Gold Hill, opinion of E. W. McGraw, 1898-99 (Box 9, Folder 196)
      - Peabody Mining Company vs. Gold Hill (9th US Circuit Court), ca. 1899 (Box 9, Folder 197-98)
    - Special projects and reports
      - Pump sketches, [1897]
        See: Oversize, Box 114, folder 2373
      - Memorandum of papers sent to C. H. Lindley, 1903 Mar 31 (Box 9, Folder 199)
      - "Early Mills and Mines" by Melville Attwood in The Mining and Electrical Review (Box 9, Folder 200)
    - Stock documents
      - Ledger, 1877-1903 (Box 9d, Folder 201)
      - Transfer journal, 1877-1903 (Box 9e, Folder 202)
      - Assessment ledger, 1878-1903 (Box 9f, Folder 203)
      - Certificates, 1877-97 (Box 9g, Folder 204)
      - Sale of delinquent stock, 1895 Dec 4
        See: Oversize, Box 94, folder 2125
      - Proxies, 1890-91 (Box 9, Folder 205)
      - Proxies, 1898-1900 (Box 9, Folder 206-07)
      - Proxies, 1903 (Box 9, Folder 208)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1895, 1903, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 209-10)
  - OPERATION RECORDS
    - Mine and mill monthly statement, 1896-97 (Box 10, Folder 211-12)
    - Weekly reports, 1896-1900 (Box 10, Folder 213-44)
    - Weekly reports, 1900-1902 (Box 11, Folder 245-72)
    - Mine development, 1896 (Box 11a, Folder 273)
    - Maps and diagrams, 1897-98 (Box bsd, folder 274)
      See also: Oversize, Box 95, folder 2142
  - ORE AND BULLION RECORDS
    - Amalgam account, 1896-98, 1902-03 (Box 11b, Folder 275)
    - Memorandum of bullion, 1902-03
      See: Oversize, Box 94, folder 2126
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS
    - Annual statement, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 276)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted fragile material. Restricted until conservation work has been completed. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
    - Annual statement, 1898 (Box 12, Folder 277)
    - Ledgers, 1877-1903 (Box 12a-12b, Folder 278-79)
    - Cash books, 1877-1903 (Box 12c-12d, Folder 280-81)
    - Monthly statements, 1896-1901 (Box 12, Folder 282-86)
    - Monthly statements, 1903 (Box 12, Folder 287)
    - Trial balances, 1890 (Box 12, Folder 288)
    - Trial balances, 1896-98 (Box 12, Folder 289-90)
      See also: Oversize, Box 114, folder 2374
    - Trial balances, 1901-03 (Box 12e, Folder 291)
    - Monthly tribute statements, 1897-98 (Box 12, Folder 292-93)
    - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1890-91 (Box 12, Folder 294-315)
      See also: Oversize, Box 95, folders 2143-50 Restricted until conservation work completed
    - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1892-97 (Box 13, Folder 316-57)
      See also: Oversize, Box 95, folders 2151-64 Restricted until conservation work completed
    - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1897 (Box 14, Folder 358-71)
      See also: Oversize, Box 95, folders 2159-64 Restricted until conservation work completed
    - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1897-98 (Box 15, Folder 372-87)
      See also: Oversize, Box 95-96, folders 2159-76 Restricted until conservation work completed
    - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1898-99 (Box 16, Folder 388-402)
      See also: Oversize, Box 96, folders 2165-83 Restricted until conservation work completed
    - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1899-1900 (Box 17, Folder 403-19)
      See also: Oversize, Box 96, folders 2177-95 Restricted until conservation work completed
    - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1900-1901 (Box 18, Folder 420-32)
      See also: Oversize, Boxes 96-97, folders 2184-2206 Restricted until conservation work completed
    - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1901 (Box 18a, Folder 433-37)
      See also: Oversize, Boxes 97, folders 2196-2206 Restricted until conservation work completed
    - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1902 (Box 19, Folder 438-49)
      See also: Oversize, Boxes 97, folders 2207-18 Restricted until conservation work completed
    - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1903 (Box 19a, Folder 450-54)
      See also: Oversize, Boxes 97, folders 2219-23 Restricted until conservation work completed
    - Bills sent to secretary for payment, 1900-02 (Box 20, Folder 455-57)
    - Receipts, 1896-1903 (Box 20a, Folder 458)
    - Check stubs, 1890-96 (Box 20b-20c, Folder 459-60)
    - Check stubs, 1899-1903 (Box 20d-20g, Folder 461-64)
  - PAY ROLL RECORDS
    - Pay roll records, 1897-1902
      See: Superintendent's statements and drafts, Boxes 13-19A, folders 316-454
    - Pay roll record, 1942 Feb (Box 20, Folder 465)
  - INVENTORY RECORDS
    - Ledger, 1897-98 (Box 20h, Folder 466)
    - Monthly mine and mill storehouse report, 1897-1902
    - Wood accounts, 1897-1900 (Box 20, Folder 467)
- Granite Hill Mining & Development Co., Series IV; 0.75
  - EXECUTIVE RECORDS
    - Insurance
      - Policy, 1899 Nov 6
        See: Oversize, Box 114, folder 2375
    - Agreements, claims, deeds
      - Agreement, indenture, lease, 1880 (Box 20, Folder 468)
      - Agreements, indentures, instruments, 1893-98 (Box 20, Folder 469-74)
        See also: Oversize, Box 94, folder 2127
      - Indentures, notice of mining location, partial abstract regarding mining claim (Box 20, Folder 475-76)
    - Court actions
      - Mary J. Larimer vs. Martin Ford (U.S. District Court), 1878-80 (Box 20, Folder 477)
      - Van Orden vs. Granite Hill, Martin Ford (California Superior Court), 1895 (Box 20, Folder 478)
      - John J. Ryan vs. Granite Hill (Dept. of Interior, General Land Office), 1898-1900, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 479-81)
      - John J. Ryan vs. Granite Hill (California Superior Court), 1900 Mar (Box 20, Folder 482-86)
        See also: Oversize, Box 98, folder 2224
    - Special projects and reports
      - Affidavits of labor performed and improvements made, 1896-98 (Box 20, Folder 487)
      - Secretary's reports, 1897 (Box 20, Folder 488)
      - Report by U.S. Surveyor Samuel J. Alderman, 1898 (Box 20, Folder 489)
  - OPERATION RECORDS
    - Daily journal T. F. Phillips, 1897-99 (Box 21, Folder 490)
    - Map (Box 21, Folder 491)
    - Maps, 1898-99, n.d. (Box bsd, folder 492)
  - ORE AND BULLION RECORDS
    - Report on bullion, amalgams, assays, and samplings, 1897 (Box 21, Folder 493)
    - Daily amalgam reports, 1897, 1899
      See: Box 21, folder 490, back of volume.
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS
    - Receipts of sale of Granite Hill Mine, Martin Ford to Company, 1895-97 (Box 21, Folder 494)
    - Tax receipt, 1898 Nov 25 (Box 21, Folder 495)
  - PAY ROLL RECORDS
    - Time book, 1896-99 (Box 21, Folder 496)
      Two sets of records in the volume, company and contract/tributer
  - OTHER MATERIAL
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1881, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 497)
- Grass Valley Water Company, Series V; 4.25
  This company started off with financing from the Original Empire Mill and Mining Company in 1884. They were bought out by the North Star in 1898, although the company was being managed by North Star as early as 1894. Further information can be found in the North Star records (Series VIII).
  - EXECUTIVE RECORDS
    - Incorporation, By-Laws, Minutes
      - Articles of incorporation, 1884 Dec (Box 21, Folder 498)
      - By-laws, 1889 Feb 1 (Box 21a, Folder 499)
      - Minutes of directors/stockholders meetings, 1884-99 (Box 21b, Folder 500)
      - Copies of minutes and material from meetings, 1889-99 (Box 21, Folder 501-13)
    - Correspondence
      - Received at San Francisco, 1885-86 (Box 22, Folder 514)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1889-90 (Box 22, Folder 515)
      - Received at San Francisco, 1893-95 (Box 22, Folder 516)
    - Agreements, claims, deeds
      - Agreements, deed, 1885-87 (Box 22, Folder 517-19)
      - Agreement, certificate of secretary of state, indenture, 1889, 1893 (Box 22, Folder 520)
      - Certificate of secretary of state, letter requesting termination of agreement, 1899-1900 (Box 22, Folder 521)
    - Special projects and reports
      - Empire - North Star Pipe, 1884-86 (Box 22, Folder 522-24)
    - Stock documents
      - Ledger, 1885-89 (Box 22a, Folder 525)
      - Transfer journal, 1885-89 (Box 22b, Folder 526)
      - Certificates (blank), n.d. (Box 22c, Folder 527)
      - Statement of issues of stock, 1892 (Box 22, Folder 528)
      - List of stockholders, 1891 May
        See: Oversize, Box 98, folder 2225
      - Irrevocable stock power, 1894 Jul 6 (Box 22, Folder 529)
      - Proxies, 1890, 1899 (Box 22, Folder 530-31)
      - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1889 (Box 22, Folder 532)
      - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1893-94 (Box 22, Folder 533)
  - OPERATION RECORDS
    - Daily water supply and log book, 1888-96 (Box 22, Folder 534)
    - Daily returns of water sold to North Star, 1894-97
      See: North Star Superintendent's statements and vouchers, Boxes 57-66, folders 1408-1502
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS
    - Annual statement, 1893 (Box 22, Folder 535)
    - Annual statement, 1895-97 (Box 22, Folder 536-38)
    - Ledger, 1885-89 (Box 22e, Folder 539)
    - Copy of ledger postings, 1885-92
      See: Oversize, Box 98, folder 2226
    - Trial balances, 1892, 1897 (Box 22, Folder 540-41)
    - Accounts with Empire Company, 1885-98 (Box 22, Folder 542)
    - Empire Company water accounts, 1892-93 (Box 22, Folder 543)
    - Water and labor accounts, 1888-97 (Box 22g, Folder 544)
    - Secretary's statement of receipts and disbursements, 1885-93 (Box 22, Folder 545)
    - Paid drafts, vouchers, receipts, 1884-86 (Box 22, Folder 546-49)
    - Paid drafts, vouchers, receipts, 1886-98 (Box 23, Folder 550-77)
      See also: Oversize, Box 114, folder 2376
    - List of drafts drawn, general, 1888-93 (Box 23, Folder 578)
    - List of drafts drawn in favor South Yuba Water Co., 1888-93 (Box 23, Folder 579)
- Massachusetts Hill Mining Company, 1866-95; Series VI; 1.5